Hey, it's Onoue.
（尾之上(おのうえ)）
あ～ どうも
尾之上ですけど
A rather interesting girl's headed your way.
Would you mind humoring her?
これから ちょっと
面白い子が行くんで
相手してやってくれませんか？
えっと 名前は…
I think her name was...
Miyamori. Miyamori Aoi.
（渡辺(わたなべ)）
宮森(みやもり)です　宮森あおい
宮森あおいだそうです
Miyamori Aoi, apparently.
Yeah. Thanks in advance.
ええ また改めてよろしく
まっ 菅野(かんの)さんなら
Kanno-san should be able to handle her.
うまく
やってくれるでしょう
もう半チャン
いきましょう
Let's go one more round.
Are all the ladies at Musani that headstrong?
（桜田）
にしてもムサニの女子は強いですね
渡辺さん 大丈夫ですか？
下克上
You hanging in there, Watanabe-san? I'd watch my back if I were you.
したら 俺は楽隠居
させてもらいますよ
When the time comes, I'll be able to retire in peace.
そういえば
相談させていただいた
By the way, what's going on with the 3rd Girls' Fighter Wing project
「第三飛行少女隊」って
we discussed the other day?
今 どうなってます？
どうって？
What do you mean?
（葛城(かつらぎ)）
うちの仕切りで
ムサニに作らせてもらえると
We talked about how we'd be delighted if you let us at
Musani turn it into a success story, remember?
うれしいなって話
したじゃないですか
Well, we'd need to sort out terms first.
そりゃ 条件次第ですよ
ですよね～
But of course.
うちの木下(きのした)誠一(せいいち)
向いてると思いますよ
I'm confident our Kinoshita Seiichi is perfect for it.
Exodus is being received well,
and we've got a great airtime slot too.
「えくそだすっ！」も
評判いいですし
枠なら うちが
持ってるのありますから
Nah, you better let us handle it instead.
え～ 弊社に
仕切らせてくださいよ
But Katsuragi-san, you've had mecha shows airing in your slot for ages now.
葛城さんのとこの枠って
ずっとメカものやってる枠でしょ？
Does Girls' Wing even fit?
「サンジョ」向きですかね？
We've recently started doing moe shows too...
（葛城）
いや 最近はちょっと
萌(も)えものも入れてますし
Musashino Animation
To be honest, Canaan, G.I., barmedea, and The born approached us too.
（尾之上）
まっ ぶっちゃけて言うと
Musashino Animation
Studio Canaan
カナン Ｇ.Ｉ. バルメディア
ザ･ボーン辺りも手 挙げてくれてて
Musashino Animation
Studio Canaan
原作者は絶対ギブリって
言ってるんですよね～
On top of that, the original LN author is demanding we get Gibli.
What about the budget?
（葛城）
予算はどうなってますか？
We're ready to secure the funds to cover everything.
うちなら すぐにでも
100パー確保できますよ
Is that so?
（桜田）
え～ ホントですか？
Well, we were actually hoping to get an earlier time slot for it.
あと放送枠は できればもっと
浅い時間帯がいいんですよね
But don't similar shows generally air in late-night slots?
（渡辺）
作品的には
夜帯じゃないんですか？
It's a huge franchise, so we want to reach a wider audience
ビッグタイトルなんで
一般層に見てもらえないと
原作の売り上げも上がらないでしょ
and boost LN sales even more.
Very well. We'll look into it.
（葛城）
分かりました 検討します
We can't just seal the deal here and now, you know.
あ～ でも さすがに今ここで
オーケーは出せないですよ
分かってますよ～
Naturally.
I'll halt negotiations with the other studios.
（尾之上）
じゃあ まあ よその話は
止めときますんで
Could you get a project plan to me ASAP?
早いとこ企画書もらえます？
Of course!
（葛城）
御意！
Ron!
（尾之上）
ロン！
（尾之上）チートイ ドラ３ 満貫
（葛城）うわっ！
Chiitoi, three dora, and mangan.
Exodus Christmas
I'm Miyamori Aoi from Musashino Animation.
I called you earlier.
（あおい）
先ほど ご連絡差し上げた―
武蔵野(むさしの)アニメーションの
宮森あおいと申します
Is Kanno Mitsuaki-san at home?
菅野光明(みつあき)さんは
いらっしゃいますか？
Kanno Mitsuaki
I'm Kanno.
菅野です
Nice to meet you. I'm Miyamori Aoi.
ハッ どうも はじめまして
宮森あおいです
You told me already.
（菅野）
それは もう聞いた
R-Right! You're right, I did!
（あおい）
あっ はい　そうですよね
すいません！
My apologies!
Come in.
（菅野）
どうぞ
How old were you when Ava aired?
「アヴァ」の頃って自分いくつ？
Pardon me, but what year was the original TV series?
（あおい）
すみません テレビは
何年だったでしょうか？
95年
'95.
Then I was 2.
（あおい）
ということは えっと… ２歳です
So you didn't watch it?
じゃあ見てないか
I rented the DVDs of the movies.
いえ 劇場版は
ＤＶＤで拝見しました
テレビシリーズは…
すみません 全部は…
But I haven't seen the entire TV series, sorry.
I see. Generation gap, I guess.
そうか そういう世代かな
木下君が監督だもんな
This is directed by Kinoshita-kun, right?
Do you know him?
（あおい）
お知り合いなんですか？
He worked as an episode director on Ava.
（菅野）
そりゃ～ 「アヴァ」の
演出やってもらったし
Looks like he's still pushing the envelope.
相変わらず ムチャしてるな～
好きだけどさ
Not bad.
Then would you take this job, please?
じゃあ この仕事 引き受けて
いただけるんでしょうか？
Could I turn these horses into fighter planes?
（菅野）
ここは馬じゃなくて
戦闘機にしていい？
Where they blow everything up?
（菅野）
んで 全部なぎ払う
Uh...
えっと あの
監督に聞いてみないと…
I'd have to ask the director.
宮森さん これをわしが
描く意味ってなんだろう？
Miyamori-san, why should I be the one drawing this?
Why did you come to ask me?
どうして わしに頼んできたの？
Or would just anyone do?
誰でもよかった？
I'm sorry.
いえ…
すみません　私 考えたら…
I thought...
I mean, I didn't consider...
あっ いえ 考えなくても
すごい失礼なお願いを菅野さんに…
It was so inconsiderate of me to ask you this.
I know that you're desperate.
せっぱ詰まってるのは分かった
Yes, but...
あっ はい　でも菅野さんのことを
よく知らずに頼むとか
I don't really know you and still...
菅野さんほどの人に…
Someone of your caliber must be...
My "caliber" makes no difference.
ほどってことはないよ
But animators are people too.
We want to be told, "Only you can do this."
けどアニメーターも人間だから
この仕事はお前にしかできないって
言われたいんだよね
I see.
（あおい）
はい
camera circles around
close up
on Akane,
Aya and Alpine
last, Follow Akane (serious)
(crying)
A grand escape with a whole herd of horses...
（菅野）
馬の大群に紛れて大脱走って
ムチャすぎて笑ったけど
It's bonkers, to say the least.
（あおい）
すみません
I'm sorry.
I don't think there are many animators out there who know how to do horses.
今は馬 描いたことのある
アニメーターなんか
そうそういないだろ
I say they should forget their flashy action scenes and focus on learning basic movements instead.
アニメーターは
派手なアクションより
もっと動きの基本を学ばにゃいかん
と思うんだけどな
No one would take this scene,
not even any of our in-house staff.
馬は社内でも
引き受けてくれる人がいなくて
I'm not surprised. It isn't easy.
まあね この内容じゃな～
Hold on.
あれ？　自分 ムサニだよね？
You're from Musani, right?
Would you look at that?
（杉江(すぎえ)）
佳境だね～
We will now begin our morning meeting.
（興津(おきつ)）
ただ今より朝礼を始めます
It's so quiet with two people gone.
（丸川(まるかわ)）
２人いないと静かだね～
Fortunately, Yano-san's father has stabilized.
（興津）
矢野(やの)さんのお父さまは
幸い容体も
安定されたということです
She will stay with him for a few days.
矢野さんは付き添いのため
数日お休みになります
Takanashi-san drove her there,
but we've had trouble reaching him since.
高梨(たかなし)さんは
矢野さんを送っていった後
連絡が取れませんでしたが
He just texted, saying he was going to eat dumplings and would be back in the afternoon.
先ほど ギョーザを食べてから
午後には戻るとのメールが来ました
（本田(ほんだ)）
ギョーザ？　なんで？
Dumplings? What's up with that?
They appear to be a local specialty.
（興津）
せっかくだからだそうです
I hope a dumpling eats him instead.
むしろ食われろ ギョーザに！
宮森さん 最終話の予定は？
Miyamori-san, how is the final episode going?
At 11:00 I have five animator meetings.
11時から作打ちが５件
Then I'll work on 3D layout outputs.
その後 ３Ｄレイアウト出力です
May I?
ちょっといい？
Go ahead.
（興津）
どうぞ
We need to hold a main staff meeting right away.
すぐにでも
全体会議やりたいんですが
When can the director join?
監督が空くの何時？
（本田）
19時以降なら…
なんの会議ですか？
About 19:00. But what would the meeting be about?
Trying to get the final episode on track.
（渡辺）
最終話の進行 ヤバいんだろ？
Some keyframes still haven't been assigned.
原画も まだ全部
まけてないみたいだし
If we don't get this settled soon,
we'll be in trouble.
今 会議しておかないと
それこそ万策尽きるぞ
（本田）
え～！　尽きますか！
Will we really?!
Let's focus on talking it over for now.
まっ とりあえず
話し合ってみよっか
Is my description of our current situation accurate?
（渡辺）
では 今 俺が言った状況で
間違いないですね
Are these Musani's darkest days?!
（太郎(たろう)）
うお～ ムサニ最大のピンチ！
I looked at the storyboards.
Sorry, Director, but this is impossible.
絵コンテ見たけど
監督 これ無理ですわ
It'd kill all the animators.
作画のカロリー高すぎる
Miyamori, can't we do the horses with CG?
宮森 馬３Ｄでやるって
線はないの？
I asked Shimoyanagi-san,
下柳(しもやなぎ)さんに聞いてみたんですが
but the final episode already has over 100 CG cuts.
They can't handle any more.
最終話の３Ｄカット
もう100カット超えてるってことで
無理だと…
（渡辺）はあ～
Director, we need to change the storyboards.
監督 絵コンテの内容
変えましょう
If you want to show the horses, keep their legs off-screen.
馬の群れを見せるのなら
フレームから足を切る
大量に見せるなら
横パンで回り込み風に軽くする
To make that many feasible,
we'll need to settle for a panning shot.
（木下）ちょっ…
（本田）何言ってんですか―
What are you saying, Watanabe-san?!
渡辺さん！
It's the climax!
ここは
クライマックスじゃないですか
If the animation gets sloppy at the climax,
it'll kill all the tension we've been building!
クライマックスで
作画がショボくなったら
臨場感が全然 伝わりませんよ！
最終話のクライマックスで
逃げるんなら
If we're lazy with the final episode's climax, then what have we been working towards this whole time?!
今まで なんのために
やってきたんだって話ですよ！
I understand that!
But Honda, what if it won't be done in time?
けどな 本田
完成しなかったらどうなる？
What if we can't make the air date?
放映できなかったらどうする
We can't let that happen.
（本田）
うっ ダメです
Not on the first direct contract project Musani's had in seven years!
Exodus!
絶対ダメ
ムサニ７年ぶりの
元請け作品なんですよ
If we ended this with our tails between our legs...
いや でも それを
妥協と諦めで終わらせるなんて…
すみません 監督
今のうちの力では
I'm sorry, Director,
but we don't have the manpower to
finish this content in the time we have.
この内容を このスケジュールで
完成させるのは無理です
You can cry if you want.
泣いてください
（木下）う…
（あおい）待ってください
Wait a moment.
（木下）うん？
（あおい）ご相談なんですが
I have a suggestion.
When I asked Kanno-san yesterday—
昨日 菅野さんに
お願いした時に…
Who's Kanno?
誰 菅野って？
Kanno Mitsuaki-san. The director of Ava.
（あおい）
菅野光明さんです
（あおい）「アヴァ」の
（太郎）マジ？　えっ なんで！
For reals?!
Why?!
どうやって会ったの？
コネ？　魔法？
H-How?! What sorcery is this?!
What did he say?
菅野さんが なんだって？
He said Musani already has someone who can draw it.
ムサニなら描ける人がいると
おっしゃっていました
Hold on. You're from Musani, right?
あれ？　自分 ムサニだよね？
Yes.
（あおい）
あっ はい
Musani's got that guy. You know.
いるじゃん ムサニなら
あの人
That guy?
（あおい）
あの人？
That geek, Sugie Shigeru-san.
おたくの杉江茂(しげる)さん
Well, he does have a seat at Musani,
確かに在籍してますが
今 メインのお仕事は
but he mainly works on
Meow and Woofie for another studio.
他社の「ニャンとワン太郎」で
It's a kids show, and the animals aren't realistic...
あれは子供向けで
リアルな動物じゃないような
Sugie-san's got the basics down pat, so he can do it.
杉江さんは
基本があるから描けるんだよ
Haven't you seen Ann the Brunette
or Samba's Adventures?
見たことない？
「茶髪のアン」とか
「サンバの冒険」とか
「アンデスチャッキー」
Or Andes Chucky?
Chucky, yes! It's my favorite anime!
あります 「チャッキー」
一番 大好きなアニメです！
Were you not aware that Sugie-san drew Chucky's opening all by himself?
もしかして知らない？
「チャッキー」のオープニング
一人で全部描いたのが杉江さん
Not to mention that one cut of Chucky running down the hill,
しかもチャッキーが
山道を駆け下りて 転んで
また走りだすのを
ふかんから回り込みで１(ワン)カット
stumbling, then running again as the camera pans in front of him.
最後に森中の動物が山を駆け下り
草原を埋め尽くして走る
After that, the animals of the forest run down the hill, across the field.
He did all that in three days.
We called it Sugie's Three Day Miracle.
その全てを たった３日
杉江３日伝説
The guy's a genius.
杉江さんは天才
あっ 何話だったか
覚えてないんですけど
I don't remember which episode it was...
The one where Chucky collapsed in the snow, and Poppy went looking for him...
チャッキーが
ツンドラで行き倒れて
それをポピーが捜しに行く
話があって…
Episode 38.
（菅野）
第38話―
“ひとりの山で”ね
All alone on the mountain,
Chucky collapses out of exhaustion.
チャッキーが ふら～っとなって
くたっと倒れる
That was Sugie-san too.
あれも杉江さん
I'm actually surprised you haven't asked him yet.
逆に言うと なんで杉江さんに
頼まないか不思議だけどね わしは
For reals?!
（太郎）マジか！
（本田）それホント？
Is that true?
So how about asking Sugie-san?
なので杉江さんに
お願いしたらどうでしょうか？
What do you say? Director? Chief AD?
監督と総作監は どう思う？
Very well.
（小笠原(おがさわら)）
かしこまりました
The characters might be inconsistent.
（渡辺）
キャラは似ないと思うけど
I don't mind, as long as I get to see Sugie-san's keyframes.
杉江さんの本気の原画が
見られるのですから
問題ありません
But would he be willing to take on something like this?
けど こういう萌(も)えもの
やりたがるかな
I'll try asking him.
（あおい）私 頼んでみます
（木下）あっ
I think he's the only one who can do this.
この仕事は
杉江さんにしかできないと思います
Sugie
Thank you very much.
（あおい）
ありがとうございます
I hope you didn't get lost on your way here.
（杉江の妻）
迷わなかった？　ここに来るまで
I made it okay.
大丈夫でした
Sorry, at his age he goes to bed early.
老人は夜 早くてね
He'll be out in just a moment.
ごめんなさいね すぐ来るから
I should be the one apologizing for barging in at this hour.
（あおい）
あっ いえ こちらこそ
夜分遅くにすみません
待たせて悪かったね
Sorry for making you wait.
あっ いえ 突然ですみません
Sorry for calling so suddenly.
First things first. Let me take a look.
まずは拝見しようか
But how do you know Andes Chucky?
Aren't you too young for that?
でも なんで あなたぐらいの
年齢の人が
「アンデスチャッキー」を
知ってるの？
I saw a rerun. It aired in the evenings.
再放送です
夕方にテレビでやっていて
I see. I also worked on that, doing tweens.
（妻）
そう　あれ 私も動画 描いてたのよ
Really? Sorry, I had no idea!
えっ？
すみません 存じ上げなくて
Miyamori-san, are the others still at the studio?
宮森さん まだ みんな
会社に残ってるかな
We need to talk this over.
（杉江）
話をしないといけないから
That's one of your bad habits.
You either talk too much or say nothing at all.
あなたの悪い癖
いつも言葉が少ないか多いのよ
杉江は受けるつもりでいるみたい
I think he's willing to take the job,
but we need to make some adjustments.
でも少し作戦が必要だって
I'll be home late from tomorrow on.
あしたから帰り遅くなるから
Then I'll have to start packing two meals for you.
お弁当２つ作らないとね
I looked over Kinoshita-kun's storyboards.
さて 木下君のコンテを
拝見しました
This aerial shot of the horses,
例えば この馬のふかん
僕の考えですが
for example, should take around half a day to complete.
このカットは半日かかります
This one, where the three of them go from one horse to another,
こっち 馬の背中を
次々に移動する３人
will take about eight hours.
これは８時間かな
How do you know?
（絵麻(えま)）
なんで分かるんだろう？　あっ
Experience.
経験からかな
Sixteen cuts would take a whole week,
16カット 全部上げるとなると
１週間かかるね
even if I worked from 9:00
until the last train every day.
９時から終電まで
１日フルに働いたとしても
Um... But...
あの… えっと！
We don't have that long, do we?
そんな時間はないよね
I can do it faster if rough keyframes would do.
だけど ラフ原でよければ
時間が短縮できる
別の人にクリンナップを
任せるということですか？
So we'd need to ask someone else to clean it up?
Yes.
（杉江）
うん　ただ僕のラフは
But young, inexperienced keyframers
might not be able to work with my lines.
原画に慣れてない若い人には
線が拾えないかもしれない
Worry not.
（小笠原）問題ありません
（絵麻）あっ…
I shall do the cleanups.
第２原画 わたくしがやります
（遠藤(えんどう)）
小笠原さんが？
You will?
Me too!
（井口(いぐち)）
私もやりま～す
Musani's most talented are doing mere cleanups?
（遠藤）
ムサニの第一線が２原って…
It would be my honor to work on Sugie-san's animal keyframes.
（小笠原）
杉江さんの動物原画なら ぜひ
I would be delighted to learn from you.
勉強させていただきます
小笠原君と井口君なら安心だ
Ogasawara-kun and Iguchi-kun can do it, I'm sure.
May I lend a hand too?
あの 俺もやらせてもらって
いいですか？
Me too!
（橋本）僕も
（清野）手伝わせてください
Please let me help!
I want to do it!
（女子）やりたいです！
（内田）私も！
Me too!
Thanks for your help.
ありがとう 助かるよ
はい！
Sure.
Let's do this together.
みんなで頑張ろう
Yeah!
（一同）
はい
For the remaining sixteen cuts, I will complete five a day.
（杉江）
残り16カット　これを
１日５カットずつ上げます
最後の１カットだけは
どうしても１日かかっちゃうね
However, the last cut will take a whole day by itself.
So four days in all.
都合４日
Kinoshita-kun, could we make some adjustments?
（杉江）
木下君 まだ修正できますか？
In cut 304, the movement of their legs needs some tweaking.
カット304
足の運びが気になるんですよ
It looks great to me...
すごくいい動きだと思いますけど
I'm sorry. I'm to blame for the issues.
すみません 僕のミスです
If you could give me three hours, I will fix it myself.
自分で直しますので
３時間だけもらえますか？
撮影 待ってくれるよう
頼んできます！
I'll ask filming to wait for it!
Sugie-san said he's really enjoying this.
（絵麻）
杉江さん 楽しいって言ってた
（あおい）
えっ ホント？
Really?
He's happy that he can still help.
（絵麻）
自分にも まだ
やれることがあるんだって
"Still"?
（あおい）
“まだ”って…
And the way he teaches is really easy to understand.
あと 杉江さんの
教えてくれることって
すごく分かりやすい
It's all about the frames necessary for the scene,
or the timing of movements.
お芝居に必要な絵のこととか
動きのタイミングのこととか
へえ～
Looking at his keyframes made me realize that anime's really about those movements.
アニメって
やっぱり動きだと思った
杉江さんの原画を見て
I want to be able to draw like that too.
私も あんなふうに
絵が描けるようになりたい
Hey there.
（矢野）
お疲れ
Yano-san! How's your father?
矢野さん お父さんは？
うん とりあえず大丈夫
He's fine, for now.
How about the final episode?
最終話どうなった？
あした ダビングでしょ？
The dubbing's tomorrow, right?
Yes! All the keyframes were done in time!
はい なんとか原撮になりました
Sugie-san did a great job—
杉江さんが頑張ってくれて
Sugie-san?
（矢野）杉江さん？
（スタッフたちの笑い声）
My ramblings about the old days aside,
（杉江）
まあ 昔話はさておき
人間を描く時以上に
意識しなくちゃいけないのは
make sure to focus more on how the legs and the torso stretch than you do for humans.
足や胴体の伸び縮み
Position the head, the shoulders, and the hips to match the movement.
それから動きに伴う頭
胸 腰の位置
Don't forget the vertical movement either.
上下していることを忘れないで
それから重心の移動だ
Consider how the center of balance shifts.
I see! You know, Sugie-san's only about a dozen years older than my dad.
へえ～ そうか
杉江さんって うちの父親より
ちょうど一回り上なんだよね
へえ～
だから父親にも
まだまだ頑張ってもらわないと
So I can't let my dad slack just yet either!
I've got plenty of work piled up too!
さて 仕事たまってるぞ
What's wrong, Katsuragi-san?
どうしたんですか？　葛城さん
I'm... I'm so happy I got to be the producer of this show!
（葛城）
俺… 俺 プロデューサー
やっててよかった
Don't jump the gun.
大げさでしょ
…っつうか まだ終わってないし
We're not done quite yet.
It's not even colored.
色もついてないですよ
Colors! E-Exodus!
いいよ！　いい
「えくそだすっ！」
Wait, isn't the size of her mouth off compared to the other movements?
あれ？
そこ 芝居と口パクの大きさ
全然 合ってなくない？
Cut 125, animation adjustment.
カット125作画修正
I'm heading out!
（太郎）
撮影 いってきま～す
Cut 175, match Alpine's mouth and expression to the scene.
カット175
あるぴんの芝居に合わせて
口パクと表情修正ですね
Okay, got it!
はい 了解です！
Good morning.
お疲れさま
お疲れさまです
Good morning!
Miyamori-san, are there days when Meeting Room 1 is available?
宮森さん 第１会議室って
空いている曜日ある？
There are.
Could I use it once a week?
（杉江）
週１くらいで
使わせてもらっていいかな？
That should be fine.
いいと思いますけど
The others asked me to start an animation workshop.
みんなから
作画のワークショップみたいなの
開いてくれって言われてね
ああ！　いいと思います！
すぐ調整します
That's a great idea! I'll make arrangements right away!
人数が決まってからでいいよ
Wait until we know how many people will attend.
More importantly, thank you, Miyamori-san.
それより… ありがとう 宮森さん
宮森さんが
仕事を振ってくれなければ
If you hadn't asked me to do this job,
I'd have ended my career as dead weight around here.
僕はムサニのお荷物で
終わるところだった
Dead weight? You're being too harsh on yourself!
お荷物だなんて
とんでもないです！
I kept telling myself I couldn't keep up with the times, priding myself on being an old-guard craftsman.
今風の絵が
描けないだなんて言って
孤高の職人を気取ってたんだね
It makes me really happy to know that I can still be useful.
自分にも まだやれることが
あるんだと分かって
とてもうれしいんだよ
Thank you!
ありがとう
Please! I should be thanking you for saving us.
そんな！
こちらこそ助けていただいて
ありがとうございました
I've loved Chucky all my life!
あの！
私 チャッキーが好きで好きで
When I was in kindergarten, I used to say
幼稚園の時は大きくなったら
I wanted to eat cacti like the
mountain hedgehog when I grew up.
山はりねずみみたいに
サボテンを食べたいとか言って
本当に食べて おなか壊して
I actually tried once and got really sick...
I still have a Chucky picture book at home!
それで 今でも実家に
チャッキーの絵本あります
I loved it so much! I still do!
それぐらい好きでした！　です！
You watched Andes Chucky and it made you smile?
Nothing could make me happier.
宮森さんが
「アンデスチャッキー」を見て
笑顔になってくれたのなら
こんなうれしいことはないよ
andes sanmyaku no chuufuku ni
On the highest peaks of the Andes
ikashita yama harinezumi ga orimashita
there lived a cool mountain hedgehog
andes chucky
Andes Chucky
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
Thank you for your patronage.
To Musashino Animation.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
Thank you for your patronage.
To Musashino Animation.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
Thank you for your patronage.
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
To Musashino Animation.
This is the coloring ups
We look forward to working with you again.
Thank you for your patronage.
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
oresama wa chucky da ze
Hey bro, I'm Chucky
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
for Exodus episode 13.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
for Exodus episode 13.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
To Musashino Animation.
Thank you for your patronage.
This is the coloring ups
for Exodus episode 13.
Praline  Yoshioka
We look forward to working with you again.
ki ni ittara koko ni ina
If you'd like to, stick around
andes sanmyaku yoi tokoro
The Andes are an awesome place
ue wa kiken na tsundora da
But the tundra on top is dangerous
Deadline Day
On cut 302, could you add a five percent overlay?
（木下）
カット302なんだけど
５％ほど寄って
パラかけられないかな？
Director, the channel won't take anything past 17:00!
監督 17時で局の受け付け
終わっちゃうんだけど
It's going to air tomorrow night!
明日の夜には放送だよ
Just one last thing! I want to add a blink!
あとちょっと ここだけ
目パチ足したいの
It's been four hours already!
…ってから もう４時間
たってるんですけど！
That channel's strict on deadlines! They won't accept it if we're late!
あの局 厳しいから時間過ぎたら
受け取ってもらえないんだよ
The final episode would only make it for the rerun slot!
最終話じゃなくて
再放送になっちゃうよ
Not to mention that horse cut is still not colored!
…ってか例の馬のカットのとこ
まだ白いままなんだけど
たった今 撮影 終わりました
制作が持ってきます
Filming just finished. A PA will bring it over.
Can't they just upload it to the server?
（葛城）
ちゃっちゃとサーバーに
上げられないの？
They've started to, but since the file's huge,
（渡辺）
今から上げますが
データ量がデータ量ですから
they're bringing it on a hard drive too.
保険をかけて持ち込みます
あ～ もうチキチキする！
I can't take this anymore!
In cut 299, the skirt's a different length than in other cuts!
（あおい）
カット299 スカートの丈が
前カットと違います
I'll fix that.
（小笠原）
こちらで直します
Miyamori-san, I added a tween frame to this.
（堂本(どうもと)）
あ～ 宮森さん―
１カット中割り足し 上がり～
（あおい）はい
Thanks!
How much longer to fix the color clash in cut 280?
（新川(しんかわ)）
カット280 パカの修正って
あとどのくらい？
About ten minutes!
（スタッフ）
あと10分くらいです
We're on the home stretch! Keep it up, people!
（新川）
ほ～い　泣いても笑っても
あと少しだよ みんな頑張れ！
In cut 341, the director wants to add more focus to the light source using effects.
（あおい）
カット341 光源意識した―
光のエフェクト情報量が
もっと欲しいので
Could you do one more take?
もう１テイクだけ
お願いしたいそうです
Sure. This is gonna knock his socks off.
（佐倉(さくら)）
よ～し
とことんゴージャスにしてやる
あと ちなみに俺からも１カット
自主リテークしていいかな？
Can I fix another one I spotted myself?
ハンディブレ
もっとカッコよくしたい
I want to touch up the handycam effect.
I'll let the people at editing know!
Ｖ編会場に連絡してきます
（太郎）ふふふ～ん♪
（キーボードを打つ音）
Done!
（太郎）
よし 飛んでけ
あっ？　うわっ 落ちた！
It crashed!
何～！
What?!
ハードディスクお待たせしました
Here's the hard drive!
Hurry! Horses! Airtime!
（葛城）
馬！　馬は？
放送！　早く 馬～！
Okay, I'm swapping it in.
（オペレーター）
では 差し替えま～す
No time to gawk! Just hurry up!
…なんて場合じゃなくて
急いで とにかく～
That's all the latest material swapped in.
（オペレーター）
はい 差し替え 全て終了しました
Starting the preview now.
それではプレビュー始めますね
Please do.
お願いします
Whoops, it crashed.
（オペレーター）
あら？　フリーズしました　ハハハ
Just a moment, it's rebooting.
（オペレーター）立ち上げ直します
（葛城）え～！
（オペレーター）
少々お待ちください
How long is a moment?!
Don't worry. We'll make it.
大丈夫 間に合いますよ
All right, it's ready. Here we go...
お待たせしました
まいりま～す
I knew she'd come!
（あるぴん）
やっぱり来てくれた
（あや）えっ？
（あかね）お姉さ～ん
Sis!
I'm here! Sorry I'm so late!
（お姉さん）
お待たせ！
ごめんね 遅れちゃって
I knew you'd come!
（あかね）
ううん 絶対
来てくれると思ってた
This is Musashino Animation.
はい 武蔵野アニメーションです
Sorry, Watanabe is out right now.
すみません
渡辺は外出してまして
（携帯電話のバイブ音）
うわっ　はい 宮森です！
I'll let him know.
This is Miyamori!
Hi. The preview just ended.
（渡辺）
お疲れさん
プレビュー終わりました
全てオーケーです
All cuts were okay.
I'll hand over a copy now, so you can let the staff go.
これからコピー回すから
スタッフ バラしていいよ
Okay!
あっ はい！
皆さん Ｖ編 無事に終わりました
Hey, everyone! Editing's done and it's all fine!
Great job!
お疲れさまでした！
（一同）お～！
（本田）やった！
（本田）しゃ～！
（太郎）やっほ～い！
Good work!
お疲れさまでした
Well done.
ご苦労さまでした
（堂本）ふう～
（新川）これで年 越せますね
No regrets going into the new year.
Not a single one!
堂々とね
Good work!
（絵麻）お疲れさまでした
（清野）お疲れ～
Okay! Thank you very much!
はい ありがとうございます
Booze! Tonight we go drinking!
飲もう！　今日は飲まなきゃ！
飲みますか～！
Shall we?!
領収書 切っていいから
It's on the studio. Go and have some fun together, everyone.
みんなでパ～ッと
やってくるといいよ
Thank you.
ありがとうございます　あっ…
Great job, Oi-chan.
お疲れさま おいちゃん
Okay, we're waiting for you!
は～い 待ってます～
監督と矢野さん 今 荻窪(おぎくぼ)だって
The director and Yano-san are at Ogikubo now.
NabeP's coming along too!
ああ ナベＰも
おっつけ来るそうです
Sugie-san?
杉江さん？
I'll pass on the party.
すまんね 僕は遠慮しておくよ
It's my rule to be in bed by 11 o'clock.
11時には布団に入る習慣なんだ
Okay. Thank you very much.
あっ はい お疲れさまでした
お疲れさまでした
Thank you.
Let's go.
（あおい）行こう
（絵麻）うん
Yeah.
The rest of the world is busy celebrating Christmas,
え～ 世間は
クリスマスではありますが
but this celebration is all our own.
それはそれ これはこれ
Thanks to your hard work, the final episode was completed quite satisfactorily and sent in!
皆さまのおかげを持ちまして
無事 最終話の納品を
済ませることができました～！
So for this occasion—
（木下）それでは ともかくも…
（太郎）あ～ ナベＰ 来た～
Oh, here's NabeP!
Sorry for running late.
遅くなりました
Hello.
（スタッフ）
お疲れさまで～す
Here, a present.
（渡辺）
ほい プレゼント
The final product: the shirobako! It's done!
白箱！　できたんだ！
If it wasn't, we wouldn't be out here.
できてなきゃ ここで
こんなことしてらんねえだろ
I wanna see!
（太郎）見たい 見たい
（あおい）えっ？
Excuse me! Can we use the screen?
すいませ～ん
デッキ貸してくださ～い
Exodus!
Episode 13
The Three of Us Together, Exodus!
Musashino Animation
（太郎）
Nine! Eight! Seven!
（太郎･本田）
（一同）
７･６･５･４
Six! Five! Four!
Three! Two! One!
３･２･１！
To Be Continued
This is Musashino Animation.
（興津）
はい 武蔵野アニメーションで
ございます
来年も
よろしくお願い申し上げます
We look forward to working with you next year.
Next time on Shirobako: "What Clouds Do You Like?"
次回
「ＳＨＩＲＯＢＡＫＯ(シロバコ)」
What Clouds Do You Like?